personalitycafe.com 2010-01-02

# Privacy Policy - PersonalityCafe

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at Administrator@admin.personalitycafe.com.

At PersonalityCafe, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by http://personalitycafe.com and how it is used. 

**Information**  
Information provided on the site is meant to complement and not replace any advice or information from a health professional

**Optional Voluntary Information**  
We offer the following free services, which require some type of voluntary submission of personal information by users:  
1\. Electronic newsletters (Dispatches)  
We will offer a free electronic newsletter to users. PersonalityCafe.com gathers the email addresses of users who voluntarily subscribe. Users may remove themselves from this mailing list by following the link provided in every newsletter that points users to the subscription management page. Users can also subscribe to the newsletters at the time of registration.  
2\. Message boards/forums  
Users of the site's Message Boards and Forums must register separately for these services (both are free of charge) in order to post messages, although they needn't register to visit the site. During registration the user is required to supply a username, password, and email address. 3\. "E-mail this to a friend" Service  
Our site users can choose to electronically forward a link, page, or documents to someone else by clicking "e-mail this to a friend". The user must provide their email address, as well as that of the recipient. This information is used only in the case of transmission errors and, of course, to let the recipient know who sent the email. The information is not used for any other purpose.  
4\. Polling  
We may offer interactive polls to users so they can easily share their opinions with other users and see what our audience thinks about important issues. Opinions or other responses to polls are aggregated and are not identifiable to any particular user. PersonalityCafe.com may use a system to "tag" users after they have voted, so they can vote only once on a particular question. This tag is not correlated with information about individual users.  
5\. Surveys  
PersonalityCafe.com may occasionally conduct user surveys to better target our content to our audience. We sometimes share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our sponsors, advertisers and partners. We never share any of this information about specific individuals with any third party.  
Children  
Consistent with the Federal Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent.  
Usage tracking  
PersonalityCafe.com tracks user traffic patterns throughout all of our sites. However, we do not correlate this information with data about individual users. PersonalityCafe does break down overall usage statistics according to a user's domain name, browser type, and MIME type by reading this information from the browser string (information contained in every user's browser).  
PersonalityCafe.com sometimes tracks and catalogs the search terms that users enter in our Search function, but this tracking is never associated with individual users. We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you.  
Cookies  
We may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain Personal Information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. PersonalityCafe.com uses cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above). Our advertising system delivers a one-time cookie to better track ad impressions and click rates.  
You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you've set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site. However, you do need cookies to participate actively in message boards, forums, polling and surveys.  
USE OF INFORMATION  
PersonalityCafe.com uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience in our network of sites, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users.  
As stated above, we use information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters and to enable users to participate in polls, surveys, message boards, and forums. We send out newsletters to subscribers on a regular schedule (depending on the newsletter), and occasionally send out special editions when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing. PersonalityCafe.com never shares newsletter mailing lists with any third parties, including advertisers, sponsors or partners.  
When we use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in Search function as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don't track which terms a particular user enters.  
PersonalityCafe.com creates aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers, sponsors and partners. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are pertinent to their needs. Because we don't track the usage patterns of individual users, an advertiser or sponsor will never know that a specific user clicked their ad. We will not disclose any information about any individual user except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public.  
SHARING OF THE INFORMATION  
PersonalityCafe.com uses the above-described information to tailor our content to suit your needs and help our advertisers better understand our audience's demographics. This is essential to keeping our service free. We will not share information about individual users with any third party, except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public.  
SECURITY  
PersonalityCafe.com operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our customers.  
OPT-OUT POLICY  
We give users options wherever necessary and practical. Such choices include:  
Opting not to register to receive our electronic newsletters.  
Opting not to participate in certain interactive areas, which completely alleviates the need to gather any personally identifiable information from our users  
YOUR CONSENT  
By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by PersonalityCafe.com. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.  
We collect the following information:  
1\. Click-stream data 2\. HTTP protocol elements 3\. Search terms 4\. User's Name 5\. Computer information  
At the user's option, we may also collect the following data:  
1\. Birth Date 2\. Email Address 3\. Telephone 4\. Business Address  
This data will be used for the following purposes:  
1\. Completion and support of the current activity. 2\. Web site and system administration. 3\. Research and development.  
This data will be used by ourselves and our agents.  
The following explanation is provided for why this data is collected:  
Data collected from all Web users: access logs, and search strings (if entered).  
At the user's option, we will collect the following data:  
1\. HTTP cookies  
This data will be used for the following purposes:  
1\. Research and development. 2\. One-time tailoring.  
This data will be used by ourselves and our agents.   

**Log Files**  
Like many other Web sites, http://personalitycafe.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**  
http://personalitycafe.com does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser. 

**DoubleClick DART Cookie**

.:: Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on http://personalitycafe.com.  
.:: Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to http://personalitycafe.com and other sites on the Internet   
.:: Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL - http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include .......   
Google Adsense  

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on http://personalitycafe.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

PersonalityCafe has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. http://personalitycafe.com privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.
